Guide to the Jorge Awapara publications, 1941-1978 UA 325
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jorge Awapara publications
1941-1978
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Awapara, Jorge, 1918-2005
UA 325
0.75 Linear Feet (1 box)
Publications by Dr. Jorge Awapara, arranged in order chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jorge Awapara was born in Arequipa Peru on January 15, 1918. He studied chemistry in Germany at the Rheinisch Wesfaelische Technische Hochschule, (now Aachen University of Technology) from 1936-39. With the onset of WWII he returned to Arequipa briefly, then transferred his studies to Michigan State University where he obtained Bachelor and Master of Science degrees in 1941 and 1942. His doctorate in Biochemistry was awarded by the University of Southern California in 1948. He was a Research Associate at the University of Texas, M. D. Anderson Hospital from 1948 until 1957 at which time he joined the faculty of Rice Institute (now Rice University) as an Associate Professor, becoming Full Professor in 1962. During his career at M. D. Anderson Hospital and Rice University he made many important contributions to the field of biochemistry which received a large number of citations in world literature. His research work was internationally known. He retired in 1984.
Scope and Contents
Publications by Jorge Awapara, arranged in order chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mrs. Jorge Awapara, 3/4/2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Biochemistry; Education
Document Types
publications
- Series I: 1941, 167661
  - The condensation of tertiary-butyl ethyl methyl carbinol with benzene in the presence of aluminum chloride, submitted for BS degree, Michigan State College, 167662 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: 1942, 167663
  - Study of the fragmentation of di-isopropyl methyl and di-isopropyl ethyl carbinols in the presence of aluminum chloride, MS thesis, Michigan State College, 167664 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III: 1944, 167667
  - Fragmentation of alcohols in the presence of aluminum chloride, 167668 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series IV: 946, 167677
  - A New Spectrophometric Method for the Determination of Vitamin A, 167679 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series V: 1947, 167665
  - A New Spectrophotometric method for the determination of vitamin A in foods and food products, PhD dissertation, University of Southern California, 167666 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series VI: 1948, 167681
  - Application of paper chromatography to the estimation of free amino acids in tissues, 167682 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Application of paper chromatography to the estimation of some free amino acids in tissues of the rat, 167684 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The relative absorption of intravenously adminstered amino acids by the liver, kidney, and muscle of the rat, 167685 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series VII: 1949, 167686
  - The quantitative relation between certain amino acids and glycogenesis as influenced by adrenalectomy and adrenal replacement, 167687 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Effect of androgen on concentration of certain amino acids in the rat prostrate, 167688 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Use of modified ninhydrin reagent in quantitative determination of amino acids by paper chromatography, 167689 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series VIII: 1950, 167690
  - Distribution of free amino acids and related substances in organs of the rat, 167691 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alanine and taurine formation from injected cysteine in the rat, 167692 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Free aminoethylphosphoric ester in rat organs and human tumors, 167693 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Application of partition chromatography to problems of amino acid metabolism, 167694 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The presence in animal organs and human blood of a peptide detected by paper chromatography, 167695 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Free y-aminobutyric acid in brain, 167696 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - y-aminobutyric acid in brain: its formation from glutamic acid, 167697 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Occurrence of free y-aminobutryic acid in brain and its formation from l-glutamic acid, 167698 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series IX: 1951, 167700
  - Paper chromatography of amino acids, 167701 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Distribution of transaminases in rat organs, 167702 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series X: 1952, 167703
  - The influence of fluoroacetate on the concentration of free amino acids in rat organs, 167704 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Action of fluoroacetate on serine and glycine metabolism in vivo, 167705 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Effect of protein depletion on the transaminating activites of some rat organs, 167710 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The influence of sex hormones in the transaminases of the accessory sex organs of the male rat, 167706 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The action of sex hormones on the metabolism of amino acids in the prostate, 167707 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2-aminoethanesulfinic acid: an intermediate in the oxidation of cysteine in vivo, 167711 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Study of the physicochemical and chemical properties of Bence-Jones protein from multiple myleloma, 167708 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series XI: 1953, 167712
  - On the mechanism of taurine formation from cysteine in the rat, 167713 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Free amino acid content and transaminase activity of lymphatic tissues and lymphosarcomas, 167714 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Oxidation of l-glutamic acid by rat heart, 167715 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series XII: 1954, 167716
  - Utilization of injected l-alanine by adrenalectomized rats, 167717 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Bence-Jones proteins of multiple myeloma, 167718 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series XIII: 1955, 167719
  - The taurine concentration of developing chick embryo, 167720 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - On the role of the adrenal cortex in metabolism of amino acids, 167723 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Enzymatic oxidation of cysteine-s to cysteine sulfinic acid, 167721 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Effect of cholic acid adminstration on taurine concentration of rat organs, 167722 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series XIV: 1956, 167724
  - The taurine concentration of organs from fed and fasted rats, 167725 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Absorption of injected taurine by rat organs, 167726 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The incorporation of serine-3-c into citrovorum factor, 167727 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Paper chromatography of urinary amino acids, 167728 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series XV: 1957, 167729 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Incorporation of serine-3-c and formaldehyde-c into methionine in vitro, 167730 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Urinary excretion of B-aminoisobutyric acid administration of thymine and nitrogen mustard, 167731 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Urinary amino acid excretion in leukemia, 167732 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series XVI: 1959, 167733 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chromatopraphic methods for the identification of biogenic amines, 167734 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A method for determination of some amino acid decarboxylases, 167735 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Free amino acids in some aquatic invertebrates, 167736 (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_0ac5fce47ad3d8eebe96d3d45bcb484b)
  - Occurrence of B-aminoisobutyric acid in myteilus edulis, 167737 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series XVII: 1960, 167738
  - Metabolism of sulfur amino acids in mytilus edulis and rangia cuneata, 167739 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sulfur metabolism in the lugworm, arenicola cristata stimpson, 167740 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series XVIII: 1962, 167741
  - Activation of DOPA decardoxylase by pyridoxal phosphate, 167742 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series XIX: 1964, 167743
  - Utilization of C14O2 for the formation of some amino acids in three invertebrates, 167744 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Parathyroid influence on removal of hydroxyproline by peritoneal lavage in the rat, 167745 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Substrate specificity of DOPA decarboxylase, 167746 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase activity in invertebrates, 167747 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series XX: 1965, 167749
  - Biosynthesis of glucose from pyruvate-2-c and aspartate -3-c in a mollusc, 167750 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series XXI: 1966, 167751
  - The Pathway of glucose degradation in some invertebrates, 167752 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series XXII: 1967, 167753
  - Formation of taurine and isethionic acid in rat brain, 167754 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Formation of y-aminobutryic acid in brain of mice treated with l-glutamic acic-y-hydrazide and pyridoxal phosphate-y-glutamyl hydrazone, 167755 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Comparative physiology: metabolism, 167756 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Alanine and succinate as end-products of glucose degradation in the clam rangia cuneata, 167757 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series XXIII: 1968, 167758
  - Effects of various substituted hydrazones and hydrazines of pyridoxal-5'-phosphate on brain glutamate decarboxylase, 167759 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Introduction to Bilogocial Chemistry (textbook manuscript copy), 167760 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series XXIV: 1969, 167761
  - Intracellular distribution of enzymes catalyzing succinate production from glucose in rangia mantle, 167762 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Effect of oxygen on the end-products of glycolysis in rangia cuneata, 167763 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series XXV: 1972, 167764
  - Stereospecificity of some invertebrate lactic dehydrogenases, 167765 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series XXVI: 1975, 167766
  - Fluctuations in DOPA decarboxylase activity with age, 167767 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series XXVII: 1976, 167768
  - Uptake of taurine by slices of rat heart and kidney, 167769 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The metabolism of taurine in the animal, 167770 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Series XXVIII: 1978, 167771
  - Substrate specificity and other properties of DOPA decarboxylase from guinea, 167772
- Series XXVIX: Undated, 167773
  - Free amino acids in invertebrates: a comparative study of their distribution and metabolism, 167774 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Oxydation de la cysteine en sulfate et taurine, 167775 (Box 1, Folder 28)